Guide to the Nathaniel Tarn Papers, ca. 1939-2000 M1132
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. Books and Manuscripts
  - NT: Interviews With [2 of 2] (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Jed Rasula & Mike Erwin original ts of unedited interview at New Hope, 9.23.73 with NT's handwritten corrections & handwritten notes, a carbon and 2 page als from JR; 37 pp. photocopy of LeeBartlett interview with LB's corrections (11.85) & a clean copy; 28 pp. photocopyof interview by same for UNM [University of New Mexico] Press book of interviews; 33 pp. photocopy of "verbatim transcript" interview by Molly McQuade (1992) for book on writers at U Chicago with NT's handwritten notes; 14 pp. edited version and 22 pp. revised version with NT's handwritten notes and 10 pp of als from MQ; 57 pp. computer printout of a 1995 interview with William Campbell (Naropa student) with NT's corrections & 48 pp. computer printout of final version with 2als from WC; photocopy of interview with L. Murphy (Rutgers Graduate) for a publication of his own (late 80s); reprint of Tarn interview by Shamoon Zamir (Cambridge University Press, 1997).
  - NT: Interviews by NT (Box 15, Folder 3)
    13 pp. carbon of original ts of Interview with Gary Snyder (1971) with Snyder's corrections (unpublished in book form); 1 tls from Robert Fagles, 1971
  - NT: Articles about (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Partial File: 25 pages photocopy of computer printout of Doris Sommer's (Amherst Coll.) 7.20.83 "America as Desire(d): NT's Poetry of the Outsider as Insider" with NT's handwritten corrections for Stanley Diamond's anthology & another version; 11 pp. of correspondence with DS; 33 pp. photocopy of ts by David Lenfest's (U Illinois Chicago Circle & Loyola U, Chicago) "NT: the Poetry of Material Transfiguration" forBoundary 2, with notes by NT & DL (DL is also author of a film on NT).
  - NT: Anthologies (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Partial file: photocopy of corrected proofs of NT's poems to be included in Stanley Diamond's Dialectical Anthropology anthology.
  - NT: Translations of NT into French (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Some 50+ pages of original carbon of NT in French by Michel Deguy with handwritten corrections, heavy handwritten corrections and handwritten notes by NT and MD, also 14 pp. photocopy for the Gallimard anthology "20 Poetes Americains"; photocopy of 1 p. of "The Jubilation" with handwritten notes by MD; msmaterials on NT's broadcasts on France Culture's program Poesie Ininterrompue for the week of 5.30 - 6.6.1976
  - NT: Italian translations (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Notes on the Italian translations of NT's poems
  - NT: Translations into Spanish (Box 15, Folder 8)
    10 page photocopy of Hector Manjarrez's translations of NT poems with ms notes; photocopy of Tomas Segovia's version of "The Great Odor of Summer" for Vuelta.
  - NT: Announcements (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Small collection of flyers on readings, publications, events etc. by NT.
  - Poetry Reading Announcements (Box 15, Folder 10)
    [Folder contains similar material to the previous folder, not originally listed by Tarn]
  - The heights of Macchu Picchu - 66: by Pablo Neruda. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    100 page working draft ms with extensive corrections, other material (Jonathan Cape/FarrarStraus)
  - Con Cuba - 1969 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Anthology of Cuban Poetry. 50 page ts and ms drafts; corrected proofs (Cape Goliard/Richard Grossman)
  - NT/VS: Stelae - 1969: by Victor Segalen. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    85+ pages of drafts ms & ts (Unicorn Press)
  - NT/PN: Selected Poems of Pablo Neruda - 1970 [1 of 3] (Box 16, Folder 4)
    [Tarn's original note reads "20 pages of drafts for the book with Robert Bly, 2 tls & carbon copy; Anthony Kerrrigan, 12 tls; W.S. Merwin, 15 tls with carbon replies and poems; Alastair Reid, 5 PC. (Jonathan Cape/Delacorte);" however, there are hundreds of pp. of ms, ts, and copied draft material]
  - NT/PN: Selected Poems of Pablo Neruda - 1970 [2 of 3] (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - NT/PN: Selected Poems of Pablo Neruda - 1970 [3 of 3] (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Rabinal Achi - 1973 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    From the Quiche Maya for Rothenberg's Shaking the Pumpkin. 75 pages of drafts [ms, ts, carbons, and photcopies]
  - NT/PN The penguin [Neruda] - 1975 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Original clean galley proofs (Penguin UK)
  - NT: On Neruda (Box 17, Folder 3)
    7 pp. ms reading notes on Neruda; 7 pp. on "Neruda & Nobel" with handwritten notes and 3 pp. original ts, NT translated, of PN's "Watergate- but which one?", also with handwritten corrections and cuttings and 7 pp. appraisal of PN, half in ms, for the NY Times with copy of NYT for 10.22.71; 5 pp. handwritten notes for "Neruda & Ethnopoetics" for Durango Conference & Sulfur with 7 pp. handwritten notes on Neruda & the Araucanians; 5 pp. carbon of the original ts for "Naming & the Matter of Matter: notes on PN's Poetics" for the Bigus Labyrinth Press book.
  - NT: Zapotec struggles- 1993 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    [Ms, ts, computer printouts, and photocopied material for poetry collection edited by Howard Campbell, translated by Tarn; not orgiinally listed by Tarn]
  - NT: miscellaneous translations (Box 17, Folder 5)
    12 pp. of original ts of NT translations of Andre Breton poems; some 40 pp. ms & ts NT translations of Michel Deguy; 15 pp. ms & ts NT translations of Theodore Enslin into French for Poesie; 12 pp. carbon of NT's translations of Tomas Segovia; 4 pp. handwritten notes on Mary De Rachelwitz; file of some 40 pp. of miscellaneous translations, includes Segovia's Spanish translation of NT's "The Great Odor of Summer;" some 25 pp. of NT's translations of Hector Manjarrez, with one tls from Manjarrez (6.11.69); 1968 program of 1968 Borges evening at the NY YM-YMHA] (NT's "Spinoza" translation read); NT revisions of translations of Czech poets: V.Holan; I. Divis; J.Skacel, etc.
  - Drafts of early translations - 1960s (Box 17, Folder 6)
    [ts, carbon, some ms, and correspondence]
  - NT: Art Work (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Original photo of NT's large collage for ICA, London's exhibition on Guillame Apollinaire; collection of photocopies of NT's drawing inscriptions of books; photocopy of The Life We Do Not Lead; collection of photocopies of NT illustrated poems; collection of photocopies of NT's drawings for an issue of Boundary 2; original ts of "Three comings to the house of leaves with Nt drawing; original mock up for NT's printing of "Three months in which to live" with NT drawing; photocopy of Hopi Katchina drawing (of which several owned by Janet Rodney).
  - Bezoar on the road, June 1978 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    [A selection from Alashka: cities (Janet Rodney and Nathaniel Tarn), appearing in small, mimeographed publication]
  - Reprints of Tarn/Mendelson journal articles (Box 18, Folder 2)
    [Nationalism and religion in Southeast Asia: a review article (Pacific Affairs, Spring 1965); Fresh frozen fenix (New Literary History, 1984-1985); Initiation and the paradox of power: a sociological approach (International Association for the History of Religions Conference, September 17-22, 1964); Towards any geography/ towards any America whatsoever (Io, 13, 1972); A messianic Buddhist association in upper Burma (Bulletin of SOAS, XXIV, 3, 1961); The heraldic vision: a cognitive model for comparative aesthetics (Alcheringa two. 2. 1976); The structural study of myth and tokenism (Association of Social Anthropologists monographs, 1967); Metaphors of relative elevation, position and ranking in Popol Vuh (Estudios de Cultura Maya, 1981); Child as father to the man in the American uni-verse (American Poetry, I, 2); Robert Redfield (from Silverman S. ed., "Totems and Teachers," Columbia University Press, 1981); Dr. Jekyll, the anthropologist, emerges and marches into the notebook of Mr. Hyde, the poet (Conjunctions, no. 6, 1983)]
  - Photocopies of miscellaneous articles, announcements, correspondence regarding Tarn (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies of journal articles, book reviews, letters to the editor, listings of radio and television appearances, etc., 1956-2000 [1 of 2] (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Photocopies of journal articles, book reviews, letters to the editor, listings of radio and television appearances, etc., 1956-2000 [2 of 2] (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 126, Folder 1)
    [Photocopied ts, for copy editor, chapters 1-11; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 126, Folder 2)
    [Photocopied ts, for copy editor, chapters 12-17; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 126, Folder 3)
    [Photocopied ts, for copy editor, chapters 18-22, appendices; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 126, Folder 4)
    [Laser print copy, color-coded corrections, chapters 1-12, 9/27/1997; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 126, Folder 5)
    [Laser print copy, color-coded corrections, chapters 13-18, 9/27/1997; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 126, Folder 6)
    [Laser print copy, color-coded corrections, chapters 18-end, 9/27/1997; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 127, Folder 1)
    [Laser print copy of appendices, first and second corrections, 9/27- 11/4/1997; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 127, Folder 2)
    [Miscellaneous editorial materials, 1996-1997; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 127, Folder 3)
    [Computer print of completed version, chapters 1-11; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 127, Folder 4)
    [Computer print of completed version, chapters 12-17; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 127, Folder 5)
    [Computer print of completed version, chapters 18-end; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 127, Folder 6)
    [Computer print version with some corrections, chapters 1-11; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 127, Folder 7)
    [Computer print version with some corrections, chapters 12-17; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 128, Folder 1)
    [Computer print version with some corrections, chapters 18-end; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. An abundance of water [original title of Scandals in the house of birds] (Box 128, Folder 2)
    [Copy of ts, found in binder, chapters 1-13, circa 1990; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. An abundance of water [original title of Scandals in the house of birds] (Box 128, Folder 3)
    [Copy of ts, found in binder, chapters 14-end, circa 1990; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 128, Folder 4)
    [Copy of ts, found in binder, chapters 1-5, circa 1991; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 128, Folder 5)
    [Copy of ts, found in binder, chapters 6-end, circa 1991; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 128, Folder 6)
    [Copy of ts, found in binder, chapters 1-14, circa 1995; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 129, Folder 1)
    [Copy of ts, found in binder, chapters 15-end, circa 1995; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 129, Folder 2)
    [Copy of ts, found in binder, chapters 1-15 (2nd copy), circa 1995; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. An abundance of waters [original title of Scandals in the house of birds] (Box 129, Folder 4)
    [Copy of ts, several chapters excluded and changed; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 129, Folder 5)
    [Copy of ts, several chapters labeled "new versions," circa 1991; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 129, Folder 6)
    [Copy of ts, labeled "latest version but has no cover," chapters 1-5, circa 1991; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds (Box 129, Folder 7)
    [Copy of ts, labeled "latest version but has no cover," chapters 6-end, circa 1991; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. An abundance of waters [original title of Scandals in the house of birds] (Box 129, Folder 8)
    [Copy of ts, chapters 1-7, some correspondence, circa 1990; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. An abundance of waters [original title of Scandals in the house of birds] (Box 130, Folder 1)
    [Copy of ts, chapters 8-13, circa 1990; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. An abundance of waters [original title of Scandals in the house of birds] (Box 130, Folder 2)
    [Copy of ts, chapters 14-end, circa 1990; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. An abundance of waters [original title of Scandals in the house of birds] (Box 130, Folder 3)
    [Copy of ts, chapters 1-9; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. An abundance of waters [original title of Scandals in the house of birds] (Box 130, Folder 4)
    [Copy of ts, chapters 10-14; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. An abundance of waters [original title of Scandals in the house of birds] (Box 130, Folder 5)
    [Copy of ts, chapters 15-19; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. An abundance of waters [original title of Scandals in the house of birds] (Box 131, Folder 1)
    [Copy of ts, chapters 20-22; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. An abundance of waters [original title of Scandals in the house of birds] (Box 131, Folder 2)
    [Copy of ts, chapters 23-end; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds [1 of 2] (Box 131, Folder 3)
    [Chapter 24, ms and ts, several versions, hand-drawn charts, miscellaneous materials; not originally listed by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Prechtel, Martin. Scandals in the house of birds [2 of 2] (Box 131, Folder 4)
  - NT: The architextures (Box 131, Folder 5)
    [Ms, ts, computer printouts, galleys, other material; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. The architextures: paperback edition 2000 (Box 131, Folder 6)
    [Copy from Chax Press; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Arc32:89, from the Architextures: Oasis, no. 100, 2000 (Box 132, Folder 1)
    [Paperback literary publication; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - Zhang Ziquing (NT in China) (Box 132, Folder 2)
    [Laser copy draft of short work on recollections of Tarn's stay in China, to accompany poems selected for publication; correspondence; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - NT: Work with Sh.[Shamoon] Zamir] (1) (Box 132, Folder 3)
    [Photocopied fax and ts of long interview of Tarn Shamoon Zamir, mid 1990s; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - NT: Work with Sh.[Shamoon] Zamir] (2) (Box 132, Folder 4)
    [Correspondence, including ts, ms, and email, 1986-1998; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - NT: Work with Sh.[Shamoon] Zamir] (3) (Box 132, Folder 5)
    [Correspondence, including ts and email; laser copies of Zamir's Scandals in the house of anthropology: notes towards a reading of Nathaniel Tarn, book review by Zamir of Scandals in the house of birds, other material, 1990s; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - NT: Work into Spanish (Box 132, Folder 6)
    [Correspondence, including ts and email; laser copies of Tarn's Paz, anthropology and the future of poetry, address delivered at Paz tribute, 1998-2000; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - NT: Witter Bynner Foundation (Box 132, Folder 7)
    [Correspondence and other material regarding Tarn's and Thomas Epstein's grant proposal for translating modern American poetry into Russian, 1998-1999; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - NT: St. Petersburg poems (Box 132, Folder 8)
    [Photocopies of poems written while in Russia, some with corrections, 1996-1998; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - NT: Proofs (Box 132, Folder 9)
    [Photocopied page proofs of St. Petersburg poems, for First Intensity #15, Fall 2000; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - NT: His work in Russian (Box 133, Folder 1)
    [Mostly copies of email regarding translation and publishing of Tarn poems in a Russian anthology, some copies of ts poetry, 1995-2000; from a more recent accession, no listing by Tarn]
  - NT: His work in Russian (2) (Box 133, Folder 2)
- Series 2. Literary Correspondence
  Unlike Series I, the next two series are further divided by Tarn into subseries, listed alphabetically and topical in substance. Series II is rather long and complex, with Subseries Q, not originally divided by Tarn, further broken down into five subsubseries to accommodate textual headings denoted in the original listing. In general, the first group of Subseries, A-K, represents a geographic breakdown of individual and group correspondence, and includes American, British, French, European, Latin American, and Australian authors. The next set of Subseries, L-O, includes Literary Critics, Artists, Scholars, and Orientalists of all nationalities. Subseries P, Publishing Files, covers Tarn's stint as editor for Jonathan Cape, London/ Richard Grossman, New York. The aforementioned Subseries Q holds files relating to Other Publishers, Radio Scripts, Other Scripts, Newspapers and Periodicals, and Miscellaneous Files. Typically, all the subseries in Literary Correspondence contain correspondence, typescript and manuscript material, drafts, copies of same, and proofs. Occasionally, there is more material present in a folder than Tarn's original listing, and, if identifiable, duly noted within brackets. Over 450 correspondents are represented in the Literary Correspondence Series, with significant material from authors and poets such as: Lee Bartlett, John Brandi, Clayton Eshelman, Kenneth Irby, Pablo Neruda, Toby Olson, Octavio Paz, Jerome Rothenberg, Gary Snyder, Arnold Wesker, Hans Ten Berge, and Elliot Weinberger. Other notable authors, scholars, and poets within the Series include: Hannah Arendt, Andre Breton, John Digby, Robert Duncan, Anselm Hollo, Ted Hughes, Edward Lucie-Smith, Jackson Mac Low, Michael McClure, Edward McDiarmid, Assia Wevill, and David Wevill. Subseries P, concerning Tarn's editorship, holds letters, notes, contracts, reports, financial statements, and other material regarding the establishment of Cape Goliard Press, along with a collection of proofs and drafts from Ted Berrigan, Michel Butor, Allen Ginsburg, Louis Zukofsky, and others. In the first of five subsubseries within Subseries Q, Other Publishers, correspondence regarding the publishing of Tarn's work with publishers such as American Poetry Books, Brillig Works Press, Jonathan Cape, Chax Press, Coffee House Press, Farrar Strauss, New Directions, Ninja Press, and Random House (mostly with Nan Talese), is found here, as well as Radio Scripts by Paul Celan, Ted Hughes, and Peter Redgrove. Additionally, Other Scripts features work by Lee Bartlett, Lindsay Hill, Jed Rasula, and Philipe Soupalt, and includes many poems and discussion sheets from the 1960s United Kingdom meetings of "The Group." Within Newspapers and Periodicals, correspondence, typescript, and proofs regarding publication of articles in ACTS, Conjunctions, First Intensity, Les Lettres Nouvelles, The Times of London, and other publications are listed. The fifth subsubseries, Miscellaneous Files, gathers together General Correspondence from 1957 through 2000 with several files of individual correspondence not included in the original accession; Poetry Reading Files, from the early 1960s through the 1990s; scripts of BBC radio broadcasts from the 1950s and 1960s; and Job Offer Files, 1969-1981. Also included here are files covering Tarn's early employment by This Week In Paris (under the pseudonym Michel Tavriger), 1948-1952; poetry festivals, conferences, and readings attended, 1963-2000; and miscellaneous material including an index card file of Tarn's early publications; correspondence with Chax Press regarding the publishing of Architextures, received in a later accession; page proofs of Tarn's 1990 translation of Pablo Neruda's Four Odes One Song; photocopied newspaper and journal articles; greeting cards, announcements, etc.; artwork and photographs; and a file of unidentified, photocopied typescipt and magazine interviews with several poets.
  - Subseries A. American Authors Single Correspondence Files
    - Benveniste, Asa (Box 18, Folder 6)
      18 tls, 2 handwritten postcards; 21 pages, 1968-1984.
    - Brandi, John (Box 18, Folder 7)
      3 als, 19 tls, 13; 3 typed postcards; 32 pages & pages of copy & art, much of it signed; "Christmas Eve, San Felipe," 5 pp. photocopied inscribed; "Return to Hopi 27.8.85," 5 pp. ts, inscribed; "Nieman Kachina, 6.2.85" 13 pp. photocopied inscribed; "Hotevilla Village, Hopi," 7 pp. photocopied; 1982-
    - Brandi, John. That back road in (Box 18, Folder 8)
      Photocopy of ts, 1983
    - Callahan, Robert (Box 18, Folder 9)
      17 tls, 2 ts; 30 pages & 4 pages copy, 1976-80.
    - Collom, Jack (Box 18, Folder 10)
      4 als, 3 tls, 5 handwritten postcards, 10 pages & 23 pages copy, 1972-
    - Corman, Cid (Box 19, Folder 1)
      5 tls, 5 pages, 1963-72.
    - Creeley, Robert (Box 19, Folder 2)
      1 sheet als addresses, 1 handwritten postcard; 1 page copy.
    - Dauenhauer, Richard & Nora (Box 19, Folder 3)
      3 als, 10 tls, 2 handwritten postcard; 14 pages & copy.
    - Davenport, Guy (Box 19, Folder 4)
      1 als, 28 tls, 5 handwritten postcards, 2 typed postcards; 42 pages, 1974-1982.
    - Dorn, Edward (Box 19, Folder 5)
      2 tls, 3 handwritten postcards; 3 pages & copy: 4 pp. of photocopied work sheets on Aztec translations with profuse notes, Alaska 1976; press cut 4 pp. interview in Apr 1992, 17 pp. photocopy "To the Z-D generation" by Ed Sanders sent by ED in 1973, 1982-
    - Duncan, Robert (Box 19, Folder 6)
      3 als, 3 tls, 8 pages, & 1 page ms notes by RD for an interview; Poems from the Margins of Thom Gunn'sMoly, 8 vo.[?] original wrappers; privately printed, presentation to NT, Notes on Jess's translation series & 6 pages original typescript, 1967-72
    - Economou, George (Box 19, Folder 7)
      10 als, 21 handwritten postcards; 21 pages & 32 pages copy, 1970-
    - Enslin, Theodore [1of 2] (Box 19, Folder 8)
      1 als, 64 tls; 81 pages & 75 pages copy, Fragmenti/Epigrammata: 40 page carbon ts, dedication to NT,1975-
    - Enslin, Theodore [2of 2] (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Eshleman, Clayton [1 of 2] (Box 20, Folder 1)